<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Biosystems Analytics Lab</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Biosystems Analytics Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Natalie G. Nelson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Natalie and Lise return from research exchange in China</title>
      <link>/post/20190809_china-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190809_china-trip/</guid>
      <description>Natalie and Lise traveled to China from July 27 - August 9 along with two other faculty, two graduate students, and six P4 undergraduate fellows to visit China Agricultural University, Zhejiang University, and Zhejiang A&amp;amp;F University and forge new collaborations. Above, the NC State group poses with colleagues at Zhejiang University in Hangzhou.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emine and Lise recognized at the 2019 Annual International Meeting of the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers</title>
      <link>/post/20190801_asabe-aim-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190801_asabe-aim-awards/</guid>
      <description>Lise and Emine continue to make the Biosystems Analytics Lab proud! Emine received an Oral Presentation Award in the Natural Resources and Environment System Technical Community for her presentation, &amp;ldquo;Using Machine Learning and Remotely Sensed Data to Develop Spatiotemporal Maps of Flood Surge and Retreat”, and Lise received 1st Place in the Engineering Ethics Video Competition along with BAE PhD student, Mahmoud Shehata. Congratulations, Emine and Lise!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emine Fidan receives NC Space Grant Graduate Research Fellowship</title>
      <link>/post/20190510_emine-space-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190510_emine-space-grant/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Emine for receiving a 2019 NC Space Grant Graduate Research Fellowship for her project, Using Machine Learning and Remotely Sensed Data to Develop Spatiotemporal Maps of Flood Surge and Retreat!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nelson to serve as Project Director on USDA NIFA-funded REEU from 2019-2023</title>
      <link>/post/20190505_p4-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190505_p4-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Natalie Nelson was awarded a grant from the USDA NIFA Agriculture and Food Research Initiative, Educational Literacy Initiative’s Research and Extension Experiences for Undergraduates grant program (grant no. 2019-67032-29074/project accession no. 1018043) to create a new REEU program at NC State: Pigs, Poultry, the Planet and Data-Driven Problem-Solving (nicknamed “P4”).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emine Fidan receives Honorable Mention for a NSF Graduate Research Fellowship</title>
      <link>/post/20190411_emine-honorablemention-nsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190411_emine-honorablemention-nsf/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Emine for this prestigious recognition from the NSF Graduate Research Fellowship Program!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam Blackman selected to present his research at the National Conference on Undergraduate Research</title>
      <link>/post/20190410_sam-ncur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190410_sam-ncur/</guid>
      <description>Sam is off to Kennesaw State University from Apr 11-13 to present his poster, &amp;ldquo;Explanatory modeling of dissolved oxygen dynamics across diverse estuarine habitats,&amp;rdquo; at NCUR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lise Montefiore named a 2019 Global Change Fellow and receives NC SG/WRRI Graduate Research Award</title>
      <link>/post/20190410_lise-globalchangefellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190410_lise-globalchangefellow/</guid>
      <description>The Southeast Climate Adaptation Science Center selected Lise for a Global Change Fellowship, and the Graduate Student Research Award was granted to her by North Carolina Sea Grant/Water Resources Research Institute for her proposal, &amp;ldquo;Spatiotemporal Reconstruction of Historical Swine CAFO Spread in North Carolina and Connections to Water Quality.&amp;rdquo; Many congratulations, Lise!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab awarded NSF funding to investigate water quality in Hurricane Florence&#39;s wake</title>
      <link>/post/20181128_nsf-rapid-florence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20181128_nsf-rapid-florence/</guid>
      <description>Drs. Angela Harris, Ryan Emanuel, Mahmoud Sharara, Natalie Nelson, Diego Riveros-Iregui, and Joshua Kearns were awarded a RAPID grant from the National Science Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Environmental Engineering program for their project entitled, &amp;ldquo;Assessing chemical and microbiological contamination in environmental waters in Eastern North Carolina after Hurricane Florence.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nelson and collaborators receive NSF grant to study connections between freshwater discharges and coastal algal blooms</title>
      <link>/post/20180910_nsf-rapid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180910_nsf-rapid/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Natalie Nelson (PI, NC State), Dr. Edward Phlips (Co-PI, UF), and Dr. Eric Milbrandt (Co-PI, Sanibel-Captiva Conservation Foundation) were awarded a RAPID grant from the National Science Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Environmental Engineering program for their project entitled, &amp;ldquo;Coastal consequences of engineered water control systems: the role of freshwater discharges in Florida&amp;rsquo;s ongoing harmful algal bloom crises.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice Alonso wins 1st Place in the Envisioning Research competition</title>
      <link>/post/20180801_alice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180801_alice/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Alice Alonso, Visiting Postdoctoral Scholar in the Biosystems Analytics Lab, wins &lt;strong&gt;First Place&lt;/strong&gt; in the Faculty &amp;amp; Staff category of the NC State Envisioning Research photography competition for her submission, &lt;em&gt;A Meeting of River &amp;amp; Sea&lt;/em&gt; (shown above).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lise Montefiore&#39;s research showcased in the CALS Student Spotlight</title>
      <link>/post/20180627_lise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180627_lise/</guid>
      <description>NC State College of Agricultural and Life Sciences News spotlighted Lise Montefiore, Biosystems Analytics Lab PhD Student, for her research on the use of data analytics to identify vulnerable estuaries in the Southeast U.S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lise Montefiore earns 2nd Place for her poster at the NC State Graduate Student Research Symposium</title>
      <link>/post/20180321_lise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180321_lise/</guid>
      <description>Lise Montefiore, Biosystems Analytics Lab PhD Student, wins &lt;strong&gt;Second Place&lt;/strong&gt; in the Agricultural Sciences and Natural Resources category of the NC State Graduate Student Research Symposium for her poster, &lt;em&gt;Coupling climate, land use, and sea level rise projections to identify threatened estuaries in North Carolina&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam Blackman takes 3rd Place in the NC Water Resources Research Institute student poster competition</title>
      <link>/post/20180315_sam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180315_sam/</guid>
      <description>Sam Blackman, Undergraduate Research Assistant in the Biosystems Analytics Lab, wins &lt;strong&gt;Third Place&lt;/strong&gt; in the NC Water Resources Research Institute student poster competition for his poster, &lt;em&gt;Quantifying seasonal variability of dissolved oxygen and pH in brackish habitats of the South Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natalie Nelson selected for the New Faces of Engineering Class of 2018 by ASABE</title>
      <link>/post/20180228_natalie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180228_natalie/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Natalie Nelson, PI of the Biosystems Analytics Lab, was chosen by the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers for the New Faces of Engineering Class of 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>