<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Biosystems Analytics Lab</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Biosystems Analytics Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Natalie G. Nelson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Principal Investigator Natalie Nelson is an Assistant Professor of Data Analytics and Integrated Modeling in the Biological &amp;amp; Agricultural Engineering Department at North Carolina State University. She leads the Biosystems Analytics Lab, studies from which take a data-intensive, management-focused, and interdisciplinary approach to the study of complex biological system dynamics. Dr. Nelson is particularly interested in questions related to estuarine and coastal water quality, land-sea connectivity, and the influence of global and local change on agroecosystem productivity in the Atlantic-Gulf Coastal Plains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/home/publications-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/publications-simple/</guid>
      <description>Asterisks indicate an author is/was a graduate (&amp;#42;) or undergraduate (&amp;#42;&amp;#42;) researcher in the Biosystems Analytics Lab
Peer-reviewed:
 NG Nelson, L Montefiore&amp;#42;, C Anthony&amp;#42;&amp;#42;, L Merriman, E Kuster, GA Fox, 2019, Undergraduate exposure to climate education in natural resources management, Transactions of the ASABE, 62(3): 831-839.
 L Smith, CN Jones, NG Nelson, 2019, Featured Collection Introduction: The Emerging Science of Aquatic System Connectivity II, Journal of the American Water Resources Association, 55(3): 526-528</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching and Training</title>
      <link>/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Research and Extension Experience for Undergraduates:
 Pigs, Poultry, the Planet, and Data-Driven Problem Solving (&amp;ldquo;P4&amp;rdquo;). Funding available for undergraduate fellowships each summer, 2019 - 2023.  Courses:
 BAE 495 / 590: R Coding for Data Management and Analysis (fall 2019, distance ed) BAE 590: Environmental and Agricultural Data Analytics and Modeling (offered every spring) BAE 495 / 590: Applied Statistics for Environmental and Agricultural Data Analysis (spring 2018)  Guest lectures:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab news</title>
      <link>/home/lab-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/lab-news/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>